# Sumanshi Karanwal

Montreal, QC (438)-866-0460 sumanshik9@gmail.com

English Hindi

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **Profile**

Technically-sound software developer effective in analysing relevant information and guiding product cycle from conception to completion. I have undertaken programming and web technologies course. Prior to that I have 3 years of work experience working as a data analyst. I am seeking to utilize broad educational background with excellent technical, programming, and analytical skills to thrive as an entry-level software developer.

# **Skills**

Front- end & Back-end	HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Node.js, PHP
Object-oriented	Java, Python, C++
Database	MySQL, PostgreSQL, Metabase
Shell-scripting	Unix
Cloud- computing	Azure, AWS
Machine learning	R, Rshiny, RMarkdown
Microsoft Office	Excel, Word, Access, PowerPoint
IDE	Android Studio, Visual Studio
Dev-ops tool	Docker
Visualisation	Tableau
Others	Git, GitHub, Scrum, Agile

# **Professional Work/Experience**

Apr 2021 - Oct 2022

#### Senior Data Analyst, Datazymes - Bangalore, India

- Development of full-fledged machine learning tools in RShiny.
- Design, develop from scratch, integrate, modify and maintain Test & Control tool for pharma clients.
- Developed Forecasting tool using RShiny.
- Troubleshoot, debug and upgrading of tools and functionalities.
- Deployment of programs and evaluating user feedback.
- Ensuring that tools are updates with the latest features and modifying them depending on changed user requirement.

Oct 2019 - Dec 2020

## Data Analyst, Rentomojo - Bangalore, India

- Developed database objects, including tables, views and materialized views using SQL.
- Produced monthly reports using advanced Excel spreadsheet functions.
- Design, develop, test, modify and monitor RShiny applications as per requirement.
- Automating and scheduling crons for daily reports, Adhoc and other data requirements
- Analysing data to explore insights of data based on problem statement.
- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs.
- Synthesized current business intelligence data to produce reports and polished presentations, highlighting findings and recommending change.

Jun 2019 – Apr 2018

#### Data Analyst, Future Group - Bangalore, India

- Automating multiple daily reports for more efficient working and bringing down the execution time for the same.
- Providing store managers with insights about the top selling products at store/category/article level on daily and weekly basis.
- Developed user interactive web-based applications for analytics based on user inputs (bill slabs, article level analysis). Use of R Markdown to generate reports with insights for product level analysis and printing images based on certain criteria.
- Visualizing big data (up to 3 crore line item of data) using R based on requirement of the brands and the category departments.
- Building season wise trackers for Purchase Orders made by the company.
- Automated One Pager reports with complete information of best-selling products in each category.
- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.

#### **Education**

2021 - Present	Programming and Internet Technologies, Attestation of College Studies Institut supérieur d'informatique - Montreal
2017 - 2018	Specialization in Data Science, Post Graduate Diploma  Manipal Academy of Higher Education – India
2014 - 2017	Computer Applications, Bachelor's degree Christ University – India

# **Projects**

**Test and Control tool** A full-fledged tool used to check how well pharma workshops or newly introduced

medications are doing in the market.

**Course Camp** A web-based platform that provides tutorials in form of videos and transcripts of those

videos to all the students.

**Cookbook** A web-based app to provide list of more than 200 recipes and pre-recorded videos of the

recipes.

# **Other Experiences**

Jan 2022 - Present

### Reception Inspector, Lufa Farms - Montreal

- Checking inventory
- Certified to receive products from supplier
- Sorting of the products and placing them at proper locations.
- Portion inventory for orders.
- Transfer of products based on purchaser's request.
- Add and removing products from inventory based to the required inventory for the day.

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

## Package Handler, Intelcom - Montreal

 Unload, sort, scan label and place packages in the designated area in preparation for the delivery team.